Lynda Foster

lyndabrf@gmail.com | Phone | LinkedIn | Github | Burbank, CA

SUMMARY

I enjoy building full stack web applications with .NET tools and am interested in exploring cloud computing technologies. I have professional client-facing experience in the Entertainment Industry and success in developing technical documentation for nontechnical team members, implementing strategic plans to optimize productivity and efficiency, and automating redundant tasks. Academic and project experience includes 2 years object-oriented programming, 1 year .NET/C# web development, and 2 years SQL and database administration.

SKILLS

- Languages: C# | JavaScript | TypeScript
- Frameworks: ASP.NET Core (MVC Web App/API, Class Library) | Entity Framework Core | React
- Databases: SQL | MySQL | MS SQL Server
- Cloud Application Platforms: GitHub | Heroku | Splunk | Azure
- Other: HTML | CSS | Regex | Bootstrap | Postman | Swagger

EDUCATION

MSc in Data Analytics | Western Governors University | Salt Lake City, UT

 Technologies: Data Mining via SQL (Oracle 12c), Python (Jupyter), R, SAS Data Visualization in Excel and Tableau

BSc in Computer Science and Accounting | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT Technologies: C++ (Visual Studio), Java (NetBeans and Eclipse), Python (PySpark), MySQL, Machine Learning, Web Development

- Co-created a 8,900+ member community of WGU Computer Science students to foster an environment of student mentoring, resource sharing, and support.
- Authored study guides that are currently distributed as a resource by program coordinators, course instructors, and students.

PROJECTS | Portfolio

Ifost42/brailleAPI

- .NET REST API, manages a database of ascii braille special symbols as defined by the International Council on English Braille.
- Swagger documentation follows Open API Specification standards.
- Implements Repository and Data Access Object design patterns.

Ifost42/blog | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application, used as a knowledge base of .NET(C#) coding and web development articles.
- Implements identity/role based access and rendering to limit article permissions to the owner while allowing users to leave comments.

Lynda Foster

- Google SMTP email service verifies user registration and forwards contact form submissions to the owner.
- Code-first approach using Entity Framework Core and PostgreSQL.

Ifost42/Franchise | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application that evaluates the coverage health of a franchise by determining which locations (in a provided csv file) are farthest apart.
- Explores Kruskal's Minimum Spanning Tree to filter locations that can pass through other locations.
- Leveraged Unit tests (TDD) to manage scope changes as the app evolved over time.

EXPERIENCE

Recovering From Religion, Kansas City, KS | Web Developer Volunteer (Part-Time) | 06/2022 - Present

- Reviewed, analyzed, developed, and modified existing React solutions in TypeScript that utilized GitHub to track issues, review pull requests, and resolve merge conflicts.
- Participated in weekly stand-ups with a team of 5 other developers to maintain, manage, and extend the management and chat web applications in an agile setting.
- Coordinated with end users to ensure requirements for features are appropriately documented and efficiently implemented.

Benefit Plans Inc, Los Angeles, CA | Employer Services Analyst | 01/2019 - 10/2022

- Developed, implemented, and maintained digital operational procedures that manage \$100M+ in monthly contribution payments to pre-taxed PH&W (pension, health, and welfare) benefit accounts.
- Produced the training knowledge base for the Employer Services department which expedited the onboarding of new employees.
- Eliminated 40% of the processing time needed to reconcile discrepancies by automating the conversion of raw data to readable format using Excel macros and PowerShell scripts.

B'nai Hayim, Sherman Oaks, CA | Technical Coordinator | 04/2018 – 09/2019

- Established a system for financial reporting, database management, and website maintenance to facilitate the merging of two separate organizations.
- Created a knowledge base to train non-technical staff to independently update their website/database, maintain financial records, reconcile bank accounts, and create monthly financial reports using Quickbooks Online.
- Normalized csv data into 1st normal form for migration into an established relational database.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner (in progress) | Splunk Core Power User | ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management | Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071